

□ (+1) 858-291-2678 | 💌 yxl190090@utdallas.edu | 🌴 yul091.github.io/liyufei.me/ | 🖸 yul091 | 🛅 Yufei(Ethan) Li | 💆 @CavMonkey

# Summary\_

I am a second-year computer science Ph.D. student from the University of Texas at Dallas (UTD). I conducted research at the intersection of natural language processing (NLP), Computer Vision (CV), and Software Engineering (SE). I also focused on the application of NLP in Data Mining and Recommender Systems, and investigated the explainable AI such as model uncertainty measurements.

# Education

#### **University of Texas at Dallas**

Dallas, TX, U.S.

Ph.D. IN COMPUTATIONAL SCIENCE

2020 - Present

Artificial Intelligence Group, CSE; Advisor: Prof. Wei Yang

# University of California, San Diego

San Diego, CA, U.S.

M.S. IN ELECTRICAL AND COMPUTER ENGINEERING

2018 - 2020

Thesis: Application of A\* and Genetic Algorithm in TSP Path Planning Problem; Advisor: Prof. Farinaz Koushanfar

## Xi'an Jiaotong University

Xi'an, Shaanxi, China

B.S. IN MECHANICAL ENGINEERING

2014 - 2018

Thesis: Aircraft fuel tank oil sloshing simulation based on SPH method and center of gravity distribution analysis; Advisor: Prof. Shuai Zheng

# **Publications**

## SHARE: a System for Hierarchical Assistive Recipe Editing.

Lı, S., **Lı, Y.**, Nı, J., McAuley, J. | 2021 arXiv:2105.08185 (CoRR) [PDF]

- Proposed a task of controllable recipe editing: adapting a base recipe to satisfy a user-specified dietary constraint to assist home cooks.
- Tackled this problem with a hierarchical framework which performs simultaneous ingredient substitution via a Set Transformer, followed by conditional instruction generation using a Copy Attention network.

## **Estimating Predictive Uncertainty Under Program Data Distribution Shift.**

**LI, Y.**, CHEN, S., YANG, W. | 2021 arXiv:2107.10989 (CoRR) [PDF]

- · Defined three real-world program distribution shifts based on practical software development scenarios.
- Investigated the effectiveness of existing uncertainty measurements under program distribution shifts and proposed a large-scale benchmark for their performance.
- · Analyzed each method's pros and cons from a logic design perspective to inspire a domain-specific uncertainty design.

## **GLIB: Towards Automated Test Oracle for Graphically-Rich Applications.**

CHEN, K.\*, LI, Y.\*, CHEN, Y., FAN, C., HU, Z., YANG, W. | 29th Foundations of Software Engineering (FSE 2021) [PDF]

- Proposed a code-based data augmentation approach for generating UI glitch images on game apps.
- · Designed & built a CNN model for UI glitch detection and localized the glitch area using a saliency map to facilitate bug fixing.

# Work Experience \_\_\_\_\_

# **NEC Laboratories America, Inc.**

Princeton, NJ, U.S.

RESEARCH INTERN, PyTorch

Jun 2021 - Aug 2021

- · Annotated name entities and relations with regular expression rules on CVE texts for distant supervision.
- $\bullet \ \ \text{Incorporated the pre-trained GPT-2 backbone into a sequence labeling framework for joint entity \& \ relation \ extraction.}$
- · Proposed a bootstrap training procedure for denoising distant labels and selecting high-quality instances.

# SeekTruth Scientific and Technical Corporation

Beijing, China

RESEARCH INTERN, TENSORFLOW

Jul 2019 - Sep 2019

- Designed and boosted an adaptive discrimination definition model for objection detection.
- Designed a light-weight CNN model for identifying the direction of videos.
- Built a joint key point & pose recognition model for character detection.

Yufei Li · Résumé 1

**Projects** 

# **GAET, Embedding Evaluation**

Dallas, TX, U.S.

RESEARCH PROJECT, PYTORCH

Jul 2020 - Sep 2020

- · Proposed a low-cost offline metric for evaluating the generalizability of code embedding in software engineering applications.
- · Patched the existing pre-trained embedding based on the semantic metamorphic relationship in vector space to improve the generalizability.

### **Negative Sampling with Bias Correlation, Data Mining**

San Diego, CA, U.S.

RESEARCH PROJECT, PYTORCH

Nov 2019 - Jun 2020

- Explained the unsuccessful performance of the popularity-based sampling scheme in terms of sampling bias introduced from the non-uniform negative sampling process.
- Proposed two ways to correct the bias and design related negative sampling distributions to boost accuracy from tradition Bayesian Personalized Ranking (BPR).

### **Pet Adoption Speed Prediction, Natural Language Processing**

San Diego, CA, U.S.

RESEARCH PROJECT, TENSORFLOW

Jan 2019 - Mar 2019

- · Parsed and tokenized the description text of pets, encoded the words with word embedding.
- Designed & built a machine learning framework to combine image features & natural language meanings for popularity prediction.

## **Automatic Delivery Vehicle Design, Path Planning**

San Diego, CA, U.S.

RESEARCH PROJECT, PYTHON & MATLAB

Mar 2019 - Jun 2019

- Incorporated the Courier and TSP travel agent problems in designing autonomous delivery vehicles.
- · Designed & built a dynamic path planning model combining genetic algorithm and A\* algorithm that for path planning.

# **Awards**

# **VEX Robotics International Competitions**

TEAM COMPETITION, C LANGUAGE

- Excellent award and runner-up in 2017 VEX Robotics World Championship, Louisville, KY, U.S..
- Excellent award and runner-up in 2016 VEX Robotics Asia Open, Beijing, China.
- First class honor in 2016 VEX Robotics China Open, Xi'an, China.

## **Scholarship Awards**

PERSONAL

- National encouragement scholarship 2017, top10% of the 300+ applicants.
- National encouragement scholarship 2016, top10% of the 300+ applicants.
- National encouragement scholarship 2015, top10% of the 300+ applicants.

YUFEI LI · RÉSUMÉ 2